hey guys Pastor Myers here I want to
invite you to check out this message
called righteousness by faith and the
mark of the beast it's going to
revolutionize the way you see the mark
and understand the mark uh so check it
out and be
blessed
[Music]
uh what I want to share with you today
is is it it it has had a tremendous
impact on me as I studied this message
out please share this link right now if
you can let people know tune in to check
this message out because I promise you I
promise you this is living Mana coming
from heaven right now what I want to do
we're going to talk about righteousness
by faith and we're going to talk about
the mark of the beast but we're going to
begin with righteousness by faith
because in order to understand the
connection between the mark of the beast
and righteousness by faith we first must
understand what righteousness by faith
is and uh what I'm going to do right now
we're going to go to our first slide but
I'm going to let you know that our very
first
slide is in fact the entire gospel
summarized into one verse the entire
gospel summarized into one verse let's
go to the screen
we're going to go to John uh chapter 1
and verse 29 John the Baptist seeing
Jesus the Bible says the next day John
seeth Jesus coming unto him and saith
Behold the Lamb of God which taketh away
the sin of the
world beloved I want you to know that
the entire
gospel is summed up in that sentence
Behold the Lamb of God which taketh away
the sin of the world that is the entire
gospel summed up in that
phrase Behold the Lamb of God which
takes away the sin of the world and I
want you to understand something here
that when the Bible says that the Lamb
of God takes away the sin of the world
that covers two aspects we're going to
go back to the screen and I want you to
see what this covers first of all it
covers the taking away of past sins
that's what we would call
justification the Forgiveness of past
sins the Lamb of God beholding the Lamb
of
God I already gave the sermon away but
let me let me just let me just pretend
like I didn't just say that Behold the
Lamb of God which takes away the sin of
the world is both past t
P past tense justification the
Forgiveness of past sins as well as
future
tense
sanctification the process of
righteousness and future sins so if if
if I can summarize it in this
way the work of the Lamb of God is in
taking away our past sins justification
and our future sins s sanctification in
other words he not only forgives what we
have done in the past but then he leads
us on a process of sanctification which
is the elimination of sin out of the
life of the believer if you're with me
so far just put a one in the chat put a
one in the chat if you understand that
this sentence Behold the Lamb of God
which takes away the sin of the world is
both talking about the Forgiveness of
past sins and and and and gaining
victory over present sin in your life
present and future sin okay so the
question is how does this happen how
does the Forgiveness of sins past and
the removal of sins future how does that
happen how does this taking away process
happens happen we're going to go back to
the Old Testament and we're going to
look at a a story in the Old Testament
that once again I'm going to say it
again is a a
summarization of the entire gospel in
fact it was a foreshadow of what John
the Baptist said back there in John 1:
29 so let's go we're going to go back to
the screen numbers 21 and beginning with
verse 4 the Bible says and they
journeyed from Mount by the way of
the Red Sea to Compass the land of Edom
and the soul of the people was much
discouraged because of the way and the
people spake against God and against
Moses wherefore have you brought us up
out of Egypt to die in the wilderness
for there is no bread neither is there
any water and our soul loatheth this
light bread and the Lord sent fiery
serpents among the people and they bit
the people and much people of Israel
died therefore the people came to Moses
and said we have sinned for we have
spoken against the Lord and against the
pray unto the Lord that he take away the
serpents from us and Moses prayed for
the people and the Lord said unto Moses
make the a firey Serpent and set it on a
pole and it shall come to pass that
everyone that is bitten when he lookth
upon it shall live everyone that is
bitten when he lookth upon it shall
live and Moses made a serpent of brass
and put it on a pole and it came to pass
that if any
if a serpent had bitten any man when he
beheld
behold when he
behold
behold the lamb of God when he
beheld The Serpent of brass he
lived y'all put a seven in the chat put
put a seven in the chat if you already
see the
connection these serpents are biting the
people and then God tells Moses I want
you to make a Brazen Serpent and put it
on a pole put it on a pole and and and
when anyone that is bitten looks beholds
beholds that
serpent he will live now come on let
let's let's break this down uh that word
po signal figuratively a token a banner
a pole a sale an N sign a
standard so here's my question what is a
flag a flag is a piece of of
cloth or similar
material typically oblong or Square
attachable by one Edge to a
pole or a rope and used as the symbol or
emblem of a country or institution wow
wow so then so then watch this this poll
that God instructs Moses to put the Ser
the the Brazen Ser on is in essence like
a
flag an emblem of a
country what country do you think this
is the emblem of put it in the chat for
me please what country do you think this
emblem
represents all right I know it's coming
cuz you have no other choice but to say
the country of
Heaven this is Heaven's flag you know a
a a a flag basically when they come up
with a SYM for flag they're saying
listen everything that we can think of
of our country we're going to summarize
with this one
symbol and God chooses a Brazen serpent
he says put that serpent on a
pole so that when anyone looks at this
flag the flag of Heaven the flag of
Salvation they're going to see something
that is going to bring
healing are y'all with me so far put a
one in the chat if you're with me so far
now I want you to catch the significance
of this because you need to understand
another word here so remember the people
were being bitten let's look at this
word bitten for a moment the Hebrew word
bitten is not Shock It Is A Primitive
root which means to strike with a sting
as a serpent figurativ figuratively
watch this y'all figuratively to oppress
with with interest on a
loone wait a minute in other words it
signifies
debt are are y'all following
this the the bite of the serpent
signifies in in a symbolic sense it
signifies
debt the word is
Usery and and for example you'll see in
Deuteronomy 29 or 23: 19 Thou shalt not
lend upon Usery to thy brother Usery of
victuals Usery of anything that is Lent
upon you lent upon Usery in other
words what God is saying here was don't
put your brother in debt now the bite of
these
serpents that word
bitten also means
debt
which tells us
beloved it speaks to us when we suddenly
remember wait a minute the wages of
sin is
death so the those that were being
bitten were being put into
debt but then the Bible says whosoever
looks beholds the
serpent come on
somebody whosoever beholds the this
serpent on the
pole will no
[Music]
longer will no longer be in debt
y'all come on Isaiah 53 Isaiah 53 he is
despised and rejected of men a Man of
Sorrows and acquainted with grief and we
hid it as we we as it were our faces
from him he was despised and we esteemed
him not surely he has borne our greef
and carried our sorrows yet we did EST
esteem him stricken smitten of God and
Afflicted but he was wounded for our
transgressions he was bruised for our
iniquities the chastisement of our peace
was upon him and with his stripes we are
healed watch this all we like
sheep have gone
astray we have turned everyone to his
own way and the lord has laid on him the
iniquity of us all he was
oppressed and he was afflicted yet he
opened not his mouth he is brought as a
lamb to the slaughter and as a sheep
before her sharers his dumb so he opened
not his mouth he was oppressed with our
debt
he took our
debt upon
himself now here is the key here is what
I want y'all to catch about
this they were
told to
look and
what what else were they told to
do let's see put it in the chat y'all
what else were they told to do they were
told to look and what else were they
told to
do that's
right that's right listen they weren't
told to do anything
else they were simply told to
look the result of looking would be to
to live they weren't told to live they
were told to
look
look and the result is you live why
because you're no longer in debt put a
one in the chat if y'all following
this all they were told to do was
look that's
it that is
it just look and the result of you
looking will be that you live
John 3:14 Jesus says this and as Moses
lifted up the serpent in the wilderness
even so the son of man must be lifted up
that whosoever believeth in in him
should not perish but have everlasting
life I want you to see that looking is
synonymous with believing in him to look
on him is to believe in him and now this
is why the Bible says in Romans 4:3 for
what say the scripture Abraham be
believed God and it was counted unto him
for
righteousness now to him that work to
him that worketh is the reward not
reckoned of Grace but of
what come on y'all but of what of debt
but to him that worketh not but
believeth on him that justify the
ungodly his faith is counted for
righteousness so watch
this if we try to work for righteousness
listen to me you guys if we try to work
for
righteousness we are in
debt we are we are going against the
very thing that the cross is trying to
get rid
of the moment we say look and I've also
got to do this we're already putting
ourselves in
debt
the result of looking is going to
produce something I'm going to come to
that in a moment but I need you to
understand this
clearly if you're if we're depending on
our works to be made right with God he
says the reward of that is debt not
Grace but
debt so so again watch this numbers
21:8 and the Lord said unto Moses make
the a fiery Serpent and set it on a pole
and it shall come to pass that everyone
that is bitten when he lookth upon it
nothing
else the action there is looking upon it
the result is shall live so now what
does it mean to look when John said
Behold the Lamb of God what does it mean
to look let's go back and that word for
look is the word it the word means means
to
gaze and when you gaze at something it
means to look steadily and
intently especially in
admiration surprise or thought he could
only gaze at her an astonishment would
be an example to look
beloved means to
gaze not to
glance but to
gaze to to to to stare at
intently and what happens is if you if
you learn to stare intently at the
symbol the flag of Heaven you begin to
see all kinds of amazing
things you see have you ever heard the
the phrase a picture is worth a thousand
words y'all ever heard
that a picture is worth a thousand
words because when you look at the
picture all you need to do is
look and things begin to just come to
man I never thought about that before
wow I never looked at it this way before
yes yet it's like a fixed
Vision God is trying to teach
us to look intently at what was done on
the cross on our behalf and the problem
that it that many of us
have is that we're not looking intently
we're not looking long enough to be able
to
catch and
understand what actually happened at the
cross for for
us I like how a lafield said H attention
on it continually I like that we're
going to come back to that in a moment
continually
see there is the look and then there is
the Gaze there is the glance
and then there is the glaze if I can
give you the example let me go back to
the
screen and let's go to the
story where this
woman I is trying to get healed the
Bible says in Matthew
5:24 and when Jesus went with
him much people followed him and
thronged him and a certain woman which
had an issue of blood 12 years and had
suffered many things of many Physicians
had spent all that she had and was
nothing made better but rather grew
worse and when she had heard of Jesus
she came in the press behind him and
touched His Garment for she said if I
may touch but his
clothes I will be whole and straightway
the Fountain of her blood was he was
dried up and she felt in her body that
she was healed of that
plague and Jesus immediately knowing in
himself that virtue had gone out of
him turned him about in the press and
said who touched my clothes
now let let's pause for a moment you
guys the Bible says here that that a
multitude of people are thronging up
against
him but this woman when she touches him
he stops because he sense he senses
something has gone out of
him virtue has gone out of him why
because it was a touch of Faith beloved
I want to suggest to you that that is
the same thing when it comes to
beholding Jesus many of us don't
understand what it means to behold Jesus
because if we did by beholding him we
would
actually begin to
receive a flow of power and virtue into
our lives but but the reason many of us
are not getting that that flow of virtue
and power is because we are glancing we
are not
gazing are y'all following me right now
we are glancing at Jesus but we're not
gazing long enough for for for that
special thing to happen where Healing
Begins to happen in within
us the Bible says in habach chapter 3
and verse four and his brightness was as
the light he had horns coming out of his
hands and there was the hiding of his
power I want you to understand beloved
that the hiding of Jesus's power is in
what he did at the
cross it is in what he did at
Calvary there is the hiding of his power
and when we learn to behold that flag
that symbol power begins to flow in us
this is why the Bible tells us in
Hebrews 12:2 it says looking unto
Jesus the author and finisher of our
faith who for the joy that was set
before him endured the cross despising
the shame and is sat down at the right
hand of the Throne of God looking unto
Jesus it it it it symbolizes a continual
action many of us get up in the
morning and we might look unto Jesus for
a few
minutes
maybe 10 maybe
15 we glance and then we go about our
day and in in our day we're not looking
at Jesus at
all but then the night rolls
around and we say okay it's time to look
at Jesus
again and beloved it's good to look at
Jesus in the morning and in the evening
but we need to learn to look at Jesus
continually
all the
time Isaiah
45:22 Isaiah 45:22 the Bible says look
unto me and be ye saved all the ends of
the Earth for I am God and there is none
else I have sworn by myself the word is
gone out of my mouth in
righteousness and shall not return that
unto me every knee shall bow every
tongue shall
swear surely say shall one say in the
Lord have I righteousness and strength
even to him shall men come and all that
are incensed against him shall be
ashamed in the Lord shall all the seed
of Israel be justified and shall
Glory by fath oh man listen Jesus is
telling us we've got to look to him to
be
saved he's telling us we have to look to
him to receive
Redemption
the Bible even speaks of Moses and it
says in Hebrews chapter 11 verse verse
27 it says this by faith he forsook
Egypt not fearing the Wrath of the king
for he endured as seeing him who is
invisible Moses endured by seeing him
who is
invisible all right come on y'all we
we're going to we're going to see
something absolutely amazing here watch
this Colossians chapter 3 Colossians
3:1 the Bible says if you then be risen
with Christ seek those things which are
above where Christ sth on the right hand
of God we are
told to keep our
gaze to seek those things which are
above meaning keep our eyes stayed on
Christ the problem many of us have is
that we spend a few minutes here a few
minutes there looking for Christ looking
at Christ but we never Gaze on him we
don't understand what it
means to actually keep our minds come on
let's read it let's read it the Bible
says Thou will keep him in perfect peace
whose mind is stayed meaning continually
focused
upon thee because he trusteth in thee do
you understand
this when we learn to keep our minds
focused on Christ watching him beholding
what he did at Calvary and and
just what is this what is this that
Christ did for me you see beloved
remember we just said a picture's worth
a thousand words as we continue to look
at that Brazen serpent on the pole we
begin to see things like
courage
sacrifice
love Mercy TR
truth if a picture's worth a th words
you could write a thousand words just
looking at that you can write words you
can write an infinite amount of words
just looking at what that picture of
Christ on the cross
symbolizes and as we watch and and
behold beloved something begins to
happen in us because you understand the
Bible says by beholding we become
changed now now check this out y'all so
so we just laid down how salvation
works the way that Jesus gets rid of our
debt is by us looking at him by
beholding the Lamb of God he gets rid of
our debt so watch this remember when God
is leading the children of Israel out of
Egypt this is an the the entire Old
Testament is an object lesson and it's a
very important one that's going to lead
us to understand once again this Mark of
the Beast issue listen in the book of
Exodus chapter 14 let's go back to the
screen after uh uh God uh uh comes to to
to to Moses and he says to Moses go to
Egypt and he tells them he's going to
deliver them and there's a Passover Lamb
that is sacrificed and they are LED out
of Egypt God is delivering them from
their past are y'all with me he's
delivering them from their past now
notice go back to the screen and and and
and here's what the Lord tells them as
they're leaving Egypt he says the Lord
shall fight for you and you shall hold
your peace come back to the screen come
back come back with me the the Lord
shall fight for you and you shall hold
your peace do you see
that God says I don't want you to do
anything I I need you to you're you're
not going to fight I will fight for you
and you're going to do what hold your
peace you're going to hold your peace so
this is God dealing with with the with
the Egyptians he says hey let me handle
this I got this there's nothing you can
do to save yourself out of this
situation I am going to deliver you I am
going to deliver you I will fight for
you and you you hold your peace so
that's Exodus 14 they they they crossed
the Red Sea and now they're getting
ready to go up against amalec and I want
you to notice this in Exodus chapter 17
there's three chapters later the Bible
says then came amalec and fought with
Israel in refidim and Moses said unto
Joshua choose us out men and go out
fight with amalec tomorrow I will stand
on top of the hill with the rod of God
in my
hand uh so Joshua did as Moses said and
fought with amalec and Moses and Aaron
and her went up to the top of the hill
and it came to pass when Moses held up
his hand that Israel prevailed and when
Mo when when he let down his hand amalec
prevailed but moses' hands were heavy
and they took a stone and put it under
him and he sat thereon and Aaron and her
stayed on upon his hands the one on the
one side the other on the other and his
hands were steady until the going down
of the sun now listen to me you
guys God says now this the first time
he's telling them now you go fight but I
need you to understand
this God had already given them the
victory please please put a one in the
chat if you understand what I'm just
what what I just
said God said listen I'm gonna I'm going
to send you Moses on top of a mountain
you're going to stretch out your hands
every time your hands are extended you
are going to have
Victory now yeah you fight but it's not
you winning the fight because I already
gave you the
victory are y'all catching
this how they fought without this
without Moses Standing On Top of the
mount the the battle would have been
over they would have lost so you know
the reason reason they won the battle
was not because of their fighting skills
but it was because Moses stood on top of
the mount like
this so beloved now what I want you to
understand this powerful object lesson
you see you see listen to this come back
with me to Numbers chapter 33 the Bible
is telling us when when God crosses uh
brings the children of Israel out of the
out of Egypt he he then is getting ready
to lead them into Canaan
into this promised
land and I want you to note how God is
going to instruct them on how they are
to
fight to gain the territory in the
promised land watch this Numbers chapter
33 numbers 33 verse 50 and the Lord
spake unto Moses in the plains of Moab
by the Jordan of Jericho saying Speak
unto the children of Israel and say unto
them when you are pass over the Jordan
into the land of Canaan then you shall
drive out all the inhabitants of the
land from before you and destroy all
their pictures and destroy all their
molten images and quite pluck up pluck
down all their high
places and you shall uh dispossess the
inhabitants of the land and dwell
therein for I have given you the land to
possess it now hold on
y'all do you see what we just
read yes they were going into to fight
but God said I've already won the
battle he's leading them out of Egypt he
says y I don't want you to do anything
I'm going to get rid of your past issues
your past slavery I got you now for the
future y'all are going to
fight but I need you to know I already
won it for
you you just have to walk in the victory
that I already got for
you do y'all see this
all you have to do is walk in the
victory that I've already promised
you okay let's keep reading let's keep
reading watch this but if you will not
drive out the inhabitants of the land
before you then it shall come to pass
that those which you let remain of them
those sins which you let remain in your
life I mean those inhabitants which you
let remain shall be Pricks in your eyes
and thorns in your SIDS and shall Vex
you in the land wherein you
dwell
he says here's how I'm going to show you
here's how I'm going to lead you to gain
territory in the land I already promised
you come back to the screen for a moment
y'all here's how here's how God tells us
I'm going to give you victory in the
land in the land in the territory
because beloved as Christians we have
territory to
conquer as Christians we have territory
to conquer y'all y'all understand what
I'm y'all understand what I'm saying
right so we're Bap we crossed the Jordan
baptism and now the Lord says now I need
you go fight but I need you to know I
I've already conquered the
territory I just need you to walk in the
victory watch watch watch come on come
on let's keep reading let's keep reading
so so uh Exodus 23 he says beware of his
voice speaking about God saying I'm
going to send my angel before you beware
of his voice provoke him not for he will
not pardon your transgressions for my
name is in him behold I send an angel
before thee to keep thee in the way and
to bring thee into the place which I
have prepared watch this if thou will
indeed obey his voice and do all that I
speak then I will be an enemy to thine
enemy and an adversary unto thine
adversary watch this for my angel shall
go before thee and bring thee in unto
the amorites and the Hittites and the
perizzites and the Canaanites and the
hivites the jebusites and I will cut
them off and I will send my fear before
thee and will drive all the people to
whom Thou shalt come I will make all
their enemies turn their backs unto unto
thee and I will send Hornets before thee
which shall drive out the hivites and
the Canaanites and the hittite from
before thee and I will not drive them
out from before thee in one year lest
the land become desolate and the beasts
of the field multiply against thee by
little and little I will drive them out
from before thee until thou be increased
and inherit the land y'all listen to
me listen to me do y'all do y'all see
what God is doing
here he's saying listen when you're
walking when when when I call you out of
your past Egyptian captivity and I
delivered you and I Justified you by
beholding the lamb Behold the Lamb of
God which takes away the sin of the
world that's the past he says now I'm
going to bring you in baptism and now
you're going to go forward as a
conqueror you're going to start
conquering territory so there's the land
of fear and there is the land of lust
and there is the land of anger and there
is the the land of of of of distrust and
the and and the land of of bitterness
and the land of unforgiveness all these
lands I need you to conquer those
territories now
listen you're not going to go in and
Conquer these territories in one day
you're not going to conquer these
territories in one year but but I will
listen to me little by
little
territory by
territory I will
conquer watch this you guys here's how
the fight was going to happen God was
going to send Hornets before them so
that they didn't even need to lift a
finger if y'all trust
me I will do the fighting for
you if you have faith in me I will make
you righteous did y'all catch that just
now
if you have faith in me I will make you
righteous little by little
sanctification is the process of a
lifetime little by little don't be
discouraged yeah there's a lot of
territory but listen to me keep your
eyes on me don't look at the Giants in
the
land don't look at the Giants in the
land keep your eyes on
me and little by
little little by
little I will drive them out from but
make no Covenant with them make no
Covenant with them don't let them stay
in the land because if you do that
they're going to be thorns in your
side I like how John Gil put it listen
to this John Gil speaking on this verse
he says little by little I will drive
them out from before thee not the beasts
of the field but the inhabitants of
Canaan who were left partly to keep up
the cities and towns that they might not
fail to ruin or till the land that it
might not be desolate and partly to be
trials and exercises of the people of
Israel and to prove whether they would
serve the Lord or
not just as the Corruptions of human
nature remain with the people of God
when converted for the trial and
exercise of their Graces that they may
have their dependence not on themselves
but on the grace of God to keep them in
his
ways to preserve them safe to eternal
glory and by completing the work of
Grace which is done
gradually that they might be made meat
for
it yeah that's powerful you guys that is
powerful little by little God leads us
into these victories but he does that by
asking us to keep keep our eyes fixed on
the Lamb of
God and in keeping our eyes fixed on the
Lamb of
God listen listen watch this y'all come
back to the screen with me and remember
this the Bible says and the Lord said
unto Joshua see I have given into thine
hand Jericho and the King thereof and
the Mighty Men of Valor before Joshua
goes into fight against
Jericho God is saying I I've given you
the
land I have given you
Jericho and so how many of you know what
happened with Jericho y'all remember and
listen as Adventist we have an issue
with the story of Jero you want to know
why watch the Bible says in Joshua
chapter 6:15 it came to pass on the
seventh day that they Rose early about
the dawning of the day and Compass the
city after the same manner seven times
only on that day they Compass the city
City seven
times they compassed the city seven
times and it came to pass at the seventh
time when the priest blew the trumpets
Joshua said unto the people shout for
the Lord has given you the city all
right y'all do y'all know what that
means that means it is very
possible that this seventh day was the
Sabbath and God has a marching around
the city seven times times now some of
you like well no it wasn't a Sabbath
because God wouldn't have had the
marching but they marched seven days
7even days back to back they
marched and listen if this was the
Sabbath then what better signal what
better
sign
okay what better sign to
demonstrate I fight for you you while
you
rest what better symbol to demonstrate
resting in Christ resting in
God and now we begin to understand yes
the Sabbath is the sign of resting it is
a
sign that that helps us to understand
that God does the work in US while we
rest right there in the story of Jericho
God fights for us God says I will I just
need you to trust me I just need you to
understand that little by little I will
do the work but your work is to
look your work is to
rest and so now some of you saying well
Pastor what about you know uh uh
Humanity must must must uh must combine
with divinity it's part God and part us
listen y'all
listen let me break this down and and
get rid of that thought for a for get
rid of that thought hopefully all
together come with me to to set 1
Timothy chapter 3:16 the Bible says
without controversy great is the mystery
of godliness God was manifest In the
Flesh justified in the spirit seen of
angels preached unto the Gentiles
believed on in the world and received up
into Glory listen to me
Jesus the word god became
flesh God in human flesh and what that
tells us beloved is yes there is to be a
cooperation between Divinity and
Humanity but listen all of that happened
in
Jesus it is his Humanity that I need not
mine my humanity is not going to
cooperate with
God so it's not my Humanity cooperating
with God's Divinity it is God's Divinity
Co operating with God's Humanity which
was personified in the person of
Jesus that's why I need to Behold the
Lamb of God to realize whoa there is
literally nothing that I can do to get
from out under this debt I can't work
can I participate can God says listen
the only thing you can do is look and if
you look and look right if you look and
look correctly the result results is
going to be
righteousness the results are going to
be right actions the results are y'all
hearing
me it is God's Humanity in the person of
Jesus
Christ so check this out y'all check
this out the Bible says in Deuteronomy
chapter 3 and I commanded you that time
saying the Lord your God has given you
this land to possess it and you shall
pass over armed before your brethren the
children of Israel all that are meat for
the war but your wives your little ones
your cattle for I know that you have
much cattle you shall abide in your
cities which I have given you watch this
watch
this until the Lord have given rest unto
your brethren now now just pause for a
second God is saying here once you
conquer the land when the entire land is
conquered the final the end result is
rest
it is
rest what I need y'all to understand
beloved what I need you to understand is
this the
Sabbath is the ultimate symbol of
righteousness by faith because it points
to the fact that we are resting in the
work that Christ did for us on the cross
we are beholding how you doing all those
righteous things by your own Works no by
beholding Jesus by beholding ing the
Lamb of God he has taken away my past
sins and he has gone before me little by
little to conquer the land to conquer
the land a a and to get rid of those
present and future sins in my life he is
the one that is Conquering on my behalf
so now I have nothing where whereof I
can say hey I was part of the process of
the
victory are y'all following there is
nothing that I can say that hey you know
what if it wasn't for my part in this no
no no no no no no all I could do was
look whoa look at what God is doing on
my
behalf Behold the Lamb of God and this
is why this is why Exodus 31 says this
the Lord spake unto Moses saying Speak
thou unto the children of Israel saying
verily my sabbaths you shall keep for it
is a sign between me and you throughout
your Generations that you may know that
I
and the Lord that does sanctify you you
don't sanctify yourself I sanctify you
you rest and I
work you rest and I work but you got to
watch me work you got to watch me work
you got to behold my work you got to
behold what I did for you at the cross
and if you can just behold if you can
just look something begins to happen
it's what I call reflection Ive
righteousness listen y'all
listen the Bible says in 2 Corinthians
3:18 but we are with open face beholding
as in a glass the glory of the Lord are
changed into the same image from glory
to glory even as by the spirit of the
Lord what I need you to understand belov
it is that
righteousness listen to me righteousness
is not an action it is a
reaction I'm gonna I'm GNA pause I'm GNA
take a sip and I'm just gonna let y'all
stew on that for a
moment let me say it
again
righteousness is not an
action it is a
reaction it is the reaction of rightly
beholding the Lamb of
God when you rightly Behold the Lamb of
God you are reacting in
righteousness this is absolutely crucial
see what is an action let's go up to the
screen what is an
action action and reaction are two
concepts that are related to each other
action refers to something that is done
while reaction refers to something that
is done in response to an
action action is the cause and reaction
is the
effect action is the cause reaction is
the
effect let me let me put that in Bible
terms we love him
because did y'all catch that just now we
love him because he first loved us the
action was Calvary the action is the
serpent on the pole the
reaction
righteousness that is the reaction
let me do it this way let's go back to
the screen and let's just read it let's
just read let's just read from
reflecting Christ page 20 listen what it
says we should be continually looking
onto Jesus the author and finisher of
our faith for by beholding him we shall
be changed into His Image our character
will be made like his we should Rejoice
that all judgment is given to the son
because in his Humanity he has become
acquainted with all the difficulties
that beset
Humanity it is
impossible it is impossible for any of
us by our own power or our own efforts
to work this change in
ourselves it is the Holy Spirit the
comforter which Jesus said he would send
in the world that changes our character
into the image of Christ and when this
is accomplished we reflect as in a
mirror the glory of the Lord watch
this that is the character of the one
who thus beholds Christ thus beholds
Christ thus beholds Christ is so like
his that one looking at him sees Christ
own character shining out as of a
mirror
imperceptibly to ourselves we are
changed day by day let's rephrase that
little by
little from our ways and will into the
ways and will of Christ into the
loveliness of his character th th we
grow up into Christ and unconsciously
reflect his image
unconsciously and then she says
professed Christians keep all together
too near the low lands of Earth their
eyes are trained to see only commonplace
things and their minds dwell upon things
uh their eyes behold so watch this you
guys watch this it's like this when you
go to the doctor right and and and the
the the doctor is going to check your
reflex he does that your knee goes up
you're not you're not doing this to try
to show the doctor you have reflexes
right you relax boom
boom
response so now this is what we would
call re reflex we're going to call this
reflexive righteousness when I Behold
the Lamb of God I start to do righteous
things the righteous things I'm doing
listen to me are not
forced before the doctor even does this
you're like oh look my reflexes are
great no you're forcing yourself to do
that and in the same way beloved listen
to me many of us are forcing ourselves
to be
righteous give me a nine in the
chat if y'all caught the significance of
what I just said many of us are forcing
ourselves to be righteous
all right what else do I need to do to
be righteous okay eat this way all right
make sure I got this okay all right
Force it's not
reactive in other words when I really
looking at the lamb we're just like well
what do I need to do to be
righteous okay so to be righteous I
don't do this I don't do this I don't do
this I do this I do this I do and so we
are forcing righteousness instead of
beholding the Lamb of God and praying
for that power of reflective
righteousness so now watch this forced
righteousness is
work forced action is
work you're working to make yourself
righteous versus
gazing to become
righteous the more i gaze at what Jesus
did for me on the cross and not just in
the morning and sometimes at night but
all day long Lord keep my gaze
continually
continually on
you so now beloved we've just come to
understand there's righteousness by
faith and then there's righteousness by
force give me a nine in the chat if you
caught
what I just
said there is righteousness by
faith looking and then there's
righteousness by
force that F can go either
[Music]
way so righteousness by forth is is me
forcing myself to be righteous me okay
make sure versus beholding the Lamb of
God and having that righteousness flow
naturally flow almost involuntarily
understand what I mean when I say
involuntarily I don't mean you're not
choosing I simply mean by choosing to
Behold the Lamb the reaction is I start
to act
righteously I start to live righteously
versus righteousness by fourth now why
is righteousness by force so dangerous
listen to me y'all in the book of
Ephesians and we guess what we're about
to get to that Mark of the Beast now cuz
y'all got the foundation laid yes
through some coughing I get it but y'all
got the the foundation laid check this
out y'all in Ephesians chapter 2 the
Bible says for by grace are you saved
through faith and that not of yourselves
it is a gift of God not of Works lest
any man should
what
[Music]
boast Now give me another word for
boasting in the chat please if I'm
boasting if I'm boasting what am I doing
give me another word for boasting what
does that represent what word comes to
mind when you think of
boasting what dangerous thing what
dangerous
thing
bragging yeah yeah bragging what else
showing off what else
what word what Bible word would you say
symbolize can best symbolize but yeah
there you go y'all pride pride pride
come on come on y'all check this out
Proverbs 16 Proverbs 16 ver8 Pride goes
before
destruction and a holy spirit before a
fall better is it to be of the humble
spirit with L with the lowly than to
divide the spoil with the proud do y'all
remember remember who who started off
with a pride problem because he thought
he could be righteous by
himself do y'all remember who y'all
remember right y'all remember Isaiah
14:12 how are thou fallen from Heaven oh
Lucifer son of the morning how art thou
cut down to the ground which did weaken
the Nations for thou H has said in thy
heart I will Ascend to Heaven I will
exalt my throne above the stars of God I
will sit also upon the Mount of the
congregation in the sides of the North
I will Ascend above the heights of the
clouds I will be like the most
high are y'all ready for
this Lucifer in Desiring to be like by
the way we all should want to be like
the most high but Lucifer said I will do
that in my own
way God wants everyone to be like him
but Lucifer said I will be like God in
my own way
so watch
this righteousness by force by work
leads to pride pride is bragging it
leads to bragging or boasting which is
pride and pride goes before destruction
and a Hoy spirit before fall just like
it happened with Lucifer in heaven and
let me share with you beloved watch this
y'all about to catch this right
now righteousness by force if you learn
to force yourself to be righteous if you
practice righteousness by force versus
righteousness by faith what will
ultimately happen is that you will begin
to exercise that same Force upon
others yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yes yes
yes righteousness by force will always
ultimately lead to oppression of
others
do do y'all catch what I'm saying do
y'all see where we're going when you
exercise righteousness by works which
means righteousness by I'm forcing
myself come on work you got to force
yourself to be righteous do this X Y and
Z when you operate on that
principle of righteousness by works
righteousness by what I do righteousness
by force you will inevitably begin to
apply that principle to to
others The Desire of Ages page 22 the
Earth was darkened through
misapprehension of God that the gloomy
Shadows might be lightened that the
world might be brought back to God
Satan's deceptive power was to be broken
this could not be done by force the
exercise of force is contrary to the
principles of God's government he
desires only the service of love and
love cannot be
commanded it cannot be won by force or
authority Patriarchs and Prophets page
34 the law of love being the foundation
of the government of God the happiness
of all intelligent beings depending upon
the perfect Accord with his great
principles of
righteousness God desires from all his
creatures the service of Love service
that Springs from an appreciation of his
character by
beholding he takes no pleasure
inforced
obedience and to all he grants freedom
of will that they may render him
voluntary service so I need y'all to
catch this God is not into forced
obedience and many of us are forcing
ourselves to be
righteous why because we're not
beholding the Lamb of God and allowing
him to do it through US little by little
naturally Lord this is your work Lord
this is your work Lord this is your work
n man you know what I used to do this
and
now
yeah yes yes yes do y'all see how this
is setting up for now now listen listen
to demonstrate that righteousness by
works will always lead to persecution
all we need to do is go to Daniel
chapter 7 and 8 to look at that power
called the little horn the Church of the
Dark Ages come on y'all remember come on
we're going there we're getting to the
Mark Daniel 11 Daniel 8:1 I want you to
notice what this little horn power the
the the papacy did during the Dark Ages
the Bible says he magnified himself even
to the prince of the host and by him the
daily sacrifice was taken away and the
place of his Sanctuary cast down may I
come on this word daily is the Hebrew
word
tamid and the first time it's used in
the Bible is in connection with the
sacrifice of the Lamb come with me
Exodus 29:38 the Bible says now this is
that which Thou shalt offer upon the
altar two lambs of the first year day by
day
continually could it be that the work of
the papacy was to take people's eyes off
of the Brazen serpent on the pole off of
the eyes of our high priest and focus it
upon things upon the Earth and thus
prepare the way for a righteousness by
works system a system in which in order
to be acceptable with God you have to do
Penance pay money do all these self
humiliating things could it be come on
y'all could it be that the real battle
here is a battle of righteousness by
faith versus righteousness by force and
so once they adopted this system of
righteousness by force in other words
righteousness by work force yourself to
these pilgrimages and force yourself to
to to to to do this and do that and and
humiliate yourself could it be that
those that this is why when those who
refuse to do this those who refuse to go
along with righteousness by works what
was their end result all you got to do
beloved is look at Daniel 7:25 which
says he shall speak great words against
the most high and shall wear out or
persecute the Saints of the most high H
so Pastor you're telling me then that
that that righteousness by force is what
leads to persecution absolutely y the
the the the Crux of the matter listen to
me y'all the Crux of the matter at the
end of time is not over one day versus
another it's over the principle of
righteousness by love righteousness by
faith versus righteousness by works you
see Jesus told us in John chapter 613
1613 he said how be it when he the
spirit of Truth is come he will guide
you into all Truth for he shall not
speak of himself but whatso he shall
hear that shall he speak and he will
show you things to come Jesus was
telling us that the church was to
partner with the the spirit so church
and spirit listen church and
spirit were to unite to symbolize
righteousness by
faith however we see in the little horn
power not a uniting of church and spirit
church and allowing the spirit to work
natural righteousness through you no
what we see is church and come on
y'all come on what do we see we see
church and state what is State it's
Manpower
Manpower not God power not Spirit power
man Power this is church and
state is in essence the the culmination
of the principle of righteousness by
works forced
righteousness and now we're going to
force everybody else to be
righteous we're going to implement laws
and rules to force y'all to be
righteous
so the Bible says at the end of time
there is this end time message the
Everlasting gospel that is to go forth
into all the world and now I just need
you to see that I'm going to read a
series of verses and I'm going to show
you this Everlasting gospel is literally
the preaching of the serpent on the pole
Look to Him and live how do I know watch
this Isaiah
49:22 thus sayi the Lord God behold I
will lift up my hand to the Gentiles and
set up my standard the word standard is
the same word word used that we saw was
used for
poll in numbers did you get that the
standard is the same word used as the
pole upon which the serpent was put I
will lift up my standard to the people
and they shall bring thy sons and into
their arms and thy daughters shall be
carried upon their shoulders the
standard is what is going to draw people
to the Lord listen to me uh uh J um
let's go let's go let's go Psalm chapter
3 verse 26 the Bible says
here and he will lift up an end sign
same word same word y'all to the nations
from far and will and will hiss unto
them from the end of the Earth and
behold they shall come with speed
swiftly what is it that Everlasting
gospel it is Christ lifted up on the
cross how about this Isaiah 11 in that
day there shall be a root of Jesse which
shall stand for an end sign of the
people same word for poll back in that
numbered story for it shall be to the to
it shall the Gentiles seek and his rest
shall be glorious how about this one and
he shall set up an end sign for the
Nations and shall assemble the outcasts
of Israel and gather together the
dispers of Judah from the four corners
of the Earth all of this beloved is the
same word
used for the serpent on the Brazen pole
the Brazen serpent on the pole that is
the Everlasting gospel it is to point
people to be Behold the Lamb of
God that takes away the sin of the world
watch this y'all the loud cry where God
pours out his Spirit upon the people
guess what that is about guess what Mees
listen come on come on Zechariah 12:2
verse verse 10 I will pour upon the
House of David and upon the inhabitants
of Jerusalem the spirit of Grace and
supplication and they shall look up upon
me whom they have pierced and they shall
mourn for him as one mourn for his only
son and shall be in bitterness for him
as one that is in bitterness for his
firstborn I need you to
understand that the final message that
is to go into all the world is a message
to look to the Lamb of God that takes
away your past sins and will give you
victory over your present and future
sins but you must look at him it is not
your work it is his work therefore you
must learn to
rest even the fall of
Babylon revolves around this end sign
being lifted up note with me Jame Isaiah
13:1 the burden of Babylon which Isaiah
the son of Amos did see lift ye up a
banner upon the high mountain exalt the
voice of them shake the hand that they
may go into the gates of the Nobles the
call for Babylon to fall in involves the
lifting up of the banner what is that
Banner it is the Brazen serpent on the
pole now come come 10 minutes and I'm
done 10 minutes and I'm done you're
saying pastor you haven't even hit the
mark of the beast yet we're about to do
that right now Revelation 14:9 the third
Angel followed them saying with a loud
voice if any man worship the Beast and
His Image and receive his Mark in his
forehead or in his hand the same shall
drink of the wine of the wrath of God
which is poured out without mixture into
the cup of his indignation and he shall
be tormented with fire and brimstone in
the presence of the Holy Angels and in
the presence of the L now why am I
reading this verse to you I simply want
you to see this that word Mark are y'all
ready for this everybody sit if you're
standing up right now if you're sitting
down you may need to stand up if you're
standing up you may need to sit down
listen to
me the Greek word for Mark is the is the
is the word carigma or Cor Ma I'm about
to put up on the screen something that's
going to blow your mind are y'all ready
for this let's go let's go to the
screen according to the theological
diction dictionary of the New Testament
volume 9 page
416 the Greek word
charagma or
charagma is an engraved etched branded
or inscribed Mark or sign closest to the
original sin
is the earliest example in and a work is
listed where charagma denotes the bite
of a
snake the bite of a
snake those who receive the mark of the
beast are bitten by The Serpent and
poisoned with
self-righteousness they force themselves
to be righteous and thus they end up
forcing others to be righteous listen to
me Seventh Day
Adventist if you are in the habit of
forcing yourself to be
righteous the Venom of the serpent is
running in your
veins and when the mark of the beast
issue comes regardless of what you know
and understand you will be United on the
same team because you got the Venom in
your blood
if you are oper if you are one of those
people who look to others be like hey
what you doing man hey what are you
wearing hey what wait you eating what
come here come here come here come here
come here let me talk no no no no you
come if you're one of
those if you're one of those people who
who feel the need to be an accuser of
the Brethren if you're one of those who
who who operate under that principle of
nobody's holy like I am and and I'm
going to persecute those who are I'm
going to I'm going to let them know that
they not holy I'm going to let them
know if you're operating in that Spirit
beloved if you're operating under
righteousness by
force I need you to understand that
regardless of your title Seventh Day
Adventist or whatever you will end up
receiving the mark because the mark of
the beast is the bite of the Venom which
is salvation by my own Works those
people that died were probably dying
when they were bitten by the serpents
they were probably trying to find their
own way to heal what can I do what can I
do and they just I look that's too
something else I got to do I got to do
something to try to save
myself this is why the Bible says that
the mark of the beast is a force issue
he causeth all both small and great rich
and for rich and poor free and bond he
causeth all he forced
all the mark of the beast beloved is a
forced righteousness forced Holiness
issue and beloved many of us are living
out the very principles of church and
state in our
lives you are living that principle in
your life how do you know you're living
that principle in your life when you
think it is partly God and partly me
partly power of God and partly power of
man that's church and state y'all that's
church that's Divine and man
power and once you're living that that
that that church and state principle in
your own life you're going to start
exercising it towards other
people and if you have that principle in
you beloved listen to me it is only a
matter of time it is only a matter of
time that you're going to find that that
principle is the spirit of of Satan
himself graci gracila the human decision
is to Behold the Lamb of God and to keep
looking at him and to stay studying him
and to stay contemplating him and to be
so locked into what he did for us on the
cross that suddenly imperceptibly you
you are starting to do righteous things
without even realizing it as we just
read earlier imperceptibly day by day
little by little I'm changing and I
didn't even I didn't even realize
it that's the human decision listen
listen when men indulge this accusing
Spirit they are not satisfied with
pointing out what they supposed to be a
defect in their brother if milder means
fail of making him do what they think
ought to be done they will resort to
compulsion just as far as lies in their
power they will force men to comply with
their ideas of what is right this is
what the Jews did in the days of Christ
and what the church has done ever since
wherever she has lost the grace of
Christ finding herself destitute of The
Power of Love she has reached out for
the strong arm of the state to enforce
her dogmas and execute her decrees here
is the secret of all religious laws that
have ever been enacted and the secret of
all persecution from the days of Abel
down to our own time Christ does not
drive but draws men unto him the only
compul compulsion which he employs is
the constraint of love when the church
begins to seek for the power the support
of secular power it is evident that she
is devoid of the power of Christ the
constraint of divine
love
are y'all catching
this somebody said well if we see our
brother in error do we not say anything
that's not what I'm saying what I'm
saying is the is the dominant use the
the use of the use of I am better than
you not coming to a brother or a sister
in love and saying hey you know that
that's not what I'm talking about
because the Bible is full of that kind
of example do y'all catch what I'm
saying but what I'm s what I'm actually
saying beloved is that forget about what
you do with others how are you doing
with
yourself it's church and state happening
in you where you are seeking
righteousness through your own power
instead of beholding the Lamb of God
which takes away the sin of the world
the mark of the beast beloved is a sting
of death it is the sting of
righteousness by works it is the
outlining of the principle between Cain
and Abel between the tree of life and
the tree of the knowledge of Good and
Evil beloved listen to me listen we know
that at the End of Time the the the
Protestant churches are going to embrace
the state and listen it will be the
manifestation of righteousness by works
which will ultimately manifest
itself in a war between two
days one day is a rest day symbolizing
rest
one day is a work day symbolizing
work beloved under these two banners the
world will be
divided righteousness by
faith versus
righteousness by
works it is the enforcing of a
law that is
Con it is the enforcing of a law
just as the tree of the knowledge of
Good and Evil and the Tree of Life were
two trees symbolizing different
principles so at the End of Time Beloved
the Sabbath Sunday issue Sabbath being
the day of rest Sunday being a
counterfeit of the Sabbath and a day of
work beloved listen to me it is not when
people who are keeping Sunday now do not
have the mark of the be it is when this
issue is enforced y'all catch this now
because now it's a demonstration of
righteousness by works and all who are
under the banner of the principle of
righteousness by works church and state
in their own lives whether you are
Adventist or all who are under that
Banner will be attracted to the mark
when it
happens all
right I got two more thought one more
thought and then we're
done see let me tell you what's going to
happen with many
Adventists when many Adventists are
faced with this issue here's what's
going to happen come with me to the
screen we got three texts left and then
we're done Matthew
2674 speaking of
Peter y'all remember what happened with
Peter when Jesus is taken captive and
they're like you are with him and then
Peter says these words then began he to
curse and to swear saying I know not the
man and immediately the
crew I got a question for you was was
Peter lying or telling the truth
when Peter said I know not the man was
he lying or telling the
truth in that moment where death was
facing Peter in the face and his time of
trouble had come and Peter said I know
not the man was he lying or was he
telling the
truth was he lying or was he telling the
truth
he was lying and he was telling the
truth he knew him but he did not know
him and beloved for many of us as we
come into this final crisis we're going
to it's going to be for many of us it's
going to be too late when we
realize I didn't know
him because Peter was telling the
truth he didn't know him the way he
should have known
him and why didn't Peter know him the
way he should have known him well let me
tell you why you see in Matthew 16 look
at what the Bible says from that time
forth Jesus began to show unto his
disciples how he must go into Jerusalem
and suffer many things of the Elders of
the of the chief priests and scribes and
be killed and raised again the third day
then Peter took him and began to rebuke
him saying nah I'm not looking at that
picture no no no no no we're not
focusing on you on the cross Jesus we
got other things to focus on you're
about to set up a kingdom so we're not
focused on you on the cross no no no no
no so Peter did not choose Peter didn't
want to see Christ on the cross he had
other and beloved listen to me many of
us because we're not focusing because
we're not beholding the Lamb of
God when that crisis comes we're going
to say the same
thing I don't know him we're going to
profess the same thing in our lives that
we never really knew
him look at how Jesus ends it this is
our last
text then said Jesus unto his
disciples if any oh let me go back but
he turned and said unto Peter get thee
behind me Satan Thou Art an offense to
me for thou savest the things that be of
that thou savest not the things that be
of God but that be of men and then the
very next verse he says this if any man
will come after me let him deny himself
and take up his
cross and follow
me
beloved everything goes back to the
Cross everything goes back to that flag
of that serpent on the
pole our prayer ought to be Lord help
me day by day Moment by moment to have
that picture of Christ on the cross
before my mind help me by faith to
believe that the longer I look at that
picture the the more powerful the work
of Christ is going to be in me not
because of my works but because I am
behold holding the Lamb of God I am I am
listen to
me I am exercising the
tamid help me to keep my mind stayed on
you and not in a not in a in a in a
glancing type of way but help me to gaze
at what you did on
Calvary because when i gaze at what you
do to Calvary love is going to be
awakened in my heart
in my soul and the righteousness is
going to be a
reaction to that
love so we got two choices y'all
righteousness by faith or righteousness
by
force are you forcing yourself to be
righteous that's a dead and
rad Lord help me to keep my ey I focused
on
you and I pray that you would work out
your righteousness in me and the Lord
says all you need to do is
look and you shall it's that simple
y'all
look and you shall not might shall live
heavenly
father I want to thank you Lord for
speaking
today thank you Lord for showing us how
simple The Plan of Salvation is you've
already given us the territory you said
all we need to do is follow your
lead and Lord you've told us what that
lead is you've told us our work is to
behold not glance but gaze upon your
side sacrifice for
us gaze scan it study it contemplate it
meditate upon it Moment by moment minute
by minute so that we can see what you
did for us and in so doing love will be
awakened by
love Lord remind us that this Mark of
the Beast issue is not so much about a
day as it is about the principles of
righteousness by faith versus
righteousness by
works and Lord may we never exercise
Force upon
ourselves and thus ultimately upon
Others May we operate under that
principle of love under the principle of
Truth under the principle of your spirit
may we Behold the Lamb of God that takes
away the sin of the world in Jesus name
we pray
[Music]
amen